So in our previous video, we have seen how to create data blocks and how to write data blocks.
And we have also seen how to update sector trailers and how to update key A and key B, So now we are
going to see how to create value blocks and value blocks are also data blocks, but these are special
type of blocks.
The value blocks are special type of blocks, which contains numbers and we can do increment operations
on those numbers and we can do decrement operation on those numbers, right?
So suppose the number is ten and we want to do increment of ten, we can do just by one command, we
can do increment by ten and it will update the number and we can do the decrement as well.
So again, it depends on your requirement what you want to do.
You can do either increment or decrement operations on value blocks.
So now we are going to do create value block first.
So let's just make our connection again.
And let's just read data.
So this is our same card which we are using throughout our exercise, and let's just do get ETR.
And we will authenticate Sector one.
And from the previous video, as you know, we have updated the keys of sector one.
So we are going to authenticate with the new updated key.
And we will authenticate block six of Sector one.
So block six is in sector one.
As you can see, the address of block six is in sector one.
So let's just authenticate and authentication success.
Let's just read.
And Reid is also success.
All the data in block six is just 000, which is our default configuration.
And let's just do right value to create a value block.
And we are going to create value block on block six.
And let's just provide a default value.
So you can provide any default value.
I'm going to start with 100.
And let's just do.
Okay?
So the value block is created.
Now let's just read data in hexadecimal format for for a moment on block six.
So over here, you can see.
The data in hexadecimal format.
So the first four bytes.
Is the data, the number which we have created through our value block.
And the next four byte is the complement of the same data.
Then again, the same number is repeated.
And then again there is a complement.
Right.
So this is how value blocks are created and this is the format and this is the standard which Mifare
classic card provides to create a value block.
Like.
So now we are going to read value block from read value.
And block number six is our value block.
So read value is 100.
So we have written 100 and reading it successfully.
Now let's just do increment operation on this block.
So Block six is our value block.
We have to provide this block each time, and let's just do increment by 20.
And let's just do.
Okay?
You can see increment value 20 and increment value success message.
And let's just read the value again on block six.
So the new value is 120.
So this is how you do increment operation.
Let's just do one more increment.
We'll do increment by ten and the block number is six.
And let's just read the value.
And the new value is 130.
Now let's just do one decrement operation as well on block six and we will decrement by 50.
And let's just do okay and decrement value success and let's just read the value.
And the new value is 80.
So this is how you create value blocks and do increment and decrement operations on value blocks.